Hello, welcome to One India Hindi. To
rescue the economy which is in trouble amid the ongoing corona crisis in the country, the
Government of India announced a package of 20 lakh crore rupees.
Finance Minister Nirmala
Sitharaman today informed about the fourth installment of this package.
This is the fourth consecutive day when
Nirmala Sitharaman addressed the media.
In fact, since last Wednesday, Nirmala Sitharaman has been
continuously giving information about the relief package of 20 lakh crore rupees through press conferences.
Every day some special announcement is being made for some sector or the other.
Finance Minister
Nirmala Sitharaman has said that the government will
notify illegal arms and ammunition. In this,
import will be banned and their
indigenous supply will be made. These factories will be
corporatized and
not privatized. One-third of the defence production has been
increased from 49 percent to 74 percent. The
Finance Minister has said that the Ordnance
Factory Board will be corporatized. Along with this,
import of high-end weapons will be banned
and their list will be prepared. She
said that year after year, arms production will be increased in India itself
and the parts which have to be
imported will be produced in the country itself.  There will be a
separate budget for this.
This will reduce expenditure on defense imports and will
benefit those companies which will
make weapons for the Indian Army. Ordnance factories and
additions will be appointed. The Finance Minister has
emphasized that
appointment is necessary to improve the functioning and not
privatization. It will be listed on the stock market.
Common people will be
able to buy its shares. The Finance Minister has said that a
public private model
airport will be developed. He
said that an airport will be auctioned
and airspace will be promoted.
1000 crores will be saved by increasing the airspace.
6 airports will be developed through the PPP model. Currently,
20 airports are open. There will be an
investment of Rs. 1000 crores on the airports.
So these were the big things said by Nirmala Sitharaman, the
most special of which was that there will be
investment of ITI in the department. That's all for now in this video.
Hello,
tell me more.